A Guide to the Rockefeller Foundation records, Treasurer, RG 7 FA117
Rockefeller Archive Center
Rockefeller Foundation records, Treasurer, RG 7
undated
Rockefeller Archive Center
Rockefeller Foundation
FA117
1 Cubic Feet Actual extent is unknown.
180 reels of microfilm.
Scope and Contents
The Foundation's archives include:
Projects General Correspondence Administration, Program and Policy China Medical Board International Health Board/Division Field Offices Treasurer's Office Comptroller Personnel Fellowships Information Services Diaries Oral Histories Counsel Secretary Minutes and Officers Actions Dockets Declinations (100F) Non-textual Materials Communications Office
Biographical / Historical
The Rockefeller Foundation
The Rockefeller Foundation was established by act of the New York State Legislature approved by the Governor on May 14, 1913, "to promote the well-being of mankind throughout the world." Between 1913 and 1928 the China Medical Board, the International Health Board, and the Division of Medical Education functioned as divisions of the Foundation, concentrating on the administration of programs in public health and medical education. A Division of Studies was created in 1923 to handle projects outside the medical field. These early years were experimental as the new foundation studied the methods of philanthropy and explored its relationships with other Rockefeller boards.
Although the Rockefeller Foundation is the largest and best known philanthropy founded by the Rockefeller family, it was neither the first nor the last to be established. The Rockefeller Institute for Medical Research (1901), the General Education Board (1902), the Rockefeller Sanitary Commission for the Eradication of Hookworm Disease (1909), and the Bureau of Social Hygiene (1911) all existed earlier. When the Foundation was created, the Sanitary Commission was disbanded. After the establishment of the Foundation, the Laura Spelman Rockefeller Memorial (1918) and the International Education Board (1923) were created.
The Rockefeller boards and their programs were reconsidered and reorganized in 1927-1928 in order to avoid overlapping programs. The International Health Board of the Foundation was disbanded and an International Health Division was organized. The China Medical Board, Inc., was established as a separately incorporated institution, and the China Medical Board of the Foundation ceased to exist. The Division of Studies was dropped and the Division of Medical Education was phased out. The Laura Spelman Rockefeller Memorial was combined with the Foundation and the Spelman Fund of New York was chartered to continue activities of the LSRM that were not absorbed by the Foundation. The International Education Board was disbanded.
As a result of this reorganization, the Foundation adopted a program which included public health work (administered by the IHD), the advancement of knowledge in the medical and natural sciences (in part taken over from the IEB), the social sciences (formerly the field of the LSRM), and the humanities and arts (shared with the GEB). The Rockefeller Institute and the Bureau of Social Hygiene were not affected by the reorganization. The program adopted by the Foundation at this time remained basically the same for the next twenty years.
As its files accumulated, the Foundation maintained a card index recording the names of institutional and individual grantees and correspondents. A microfilm copy of this index is available at the Archive Center.
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
The archival material has been reformatted. Access to the original archival material is restricted. User copies of the microfilm are available for scholarly access.
Conditions Governing Access
Material more than twenty years old is open for scholarly research.
Philanthropy; Humanities; Life sciences; Medical sciences; Charities; Agriculture; Philanthropy -- United States; Public health; Charitable uses, trusts, and foundations; Rockefeller Foundation
- Grants In Aid - A-H (Reel 1)
- Grants In Aid - I-Z (Reel 2)
- Grants in Aid - Agriculture, 1959, 1968-1972 (Reel 3)
- Grants In Aid - Agriculture 1953-1959, 1960-1962 (Reel 4)
- Grants In Aid - Agriculture 1966-1967 (Reel 5)
- Grants In Aid - Humanities 1963-65 (Reel 6)
- Grants In Aid - Humanities 1948-1952, Arts 1965-1969, 1948-1952, 1965-1969 (Reel 7)
- Grants In Aid - Humanities 1953-1960 (Reel 8)
- Grants In Aid - Humanities 1960-1964 (Reel 9)
- Grants in Aid - Humanities 1965-1966, 1970-1973 (Reel 10)
- Grants in Aid - Humanities 1934 (Reel 11)
- Grants in Aid - Humanities 1967-1972 (Reel 12)
- Grants in Aid - Social Sciences 1948-1953, Medical 1961-1962, 1948-1953, 1961-1962 (Reel 13)
- Grants in Aid - Social Sciences - Bio./Med. 1958-1959 (Reel 14)
- Grants in Aid - Med./P.H. 1947-1951, Social Sciences 1954-1960, 1947-1951, 1954-1960 (Reel 15)
- Grants in Aid - Medical Sciences (Reel 16)
- Grants in Aid - Medical 1959-1960, 1966-1967 (Reel 17)
- Grants in Aid - Nat. Sciences 1951-1954, Medical 1963-1965, 1951-1954, 1963-1965 (Reel 18)
- Grants in Aid - Bio./Med. 1955-1957, B.M.S. 1968-1971, 1955-1957, 1968-1971 (Reel 19)
- Grants in Aid - Med./P.H. 1952-1954, 1955-1959 (Reel 20)
- Grants in Aid - Scholars/Visits (Reel 21)
- Grants in Aid - Nat. Sciences, 1934-1950 (Reel 22)
- Grants in Aid - Training of Health Workers (Reel 23)
- Grants in Aid, 1936-1952 (Reel 24)
- Vouchers - Treasurer's Reports, #20404-18038 (Reel 25)
- Vouchers - Treasurer's Reports, #18037B-24304 (Reel 26)
- Vouchers - Treasurer's Reports, #24303-21240 (Reel 27)
- Vouchers - Treasurer's Reports, #21239-28722 (Reel 28)
- Vouchers - Treasurer's Reports, #28721-33177 (Reel 29)
- Vouchers - Treasurer's Reports, #33176-30827 (Reel 30)
- Vouchers - Treasurer's Reports, #30826-35103 (Reel 31)
- Vouchers - Treasurer's Reports, #35102-39482 (Reel 32)
- Vouchers - Treasurer's Reports, #39481-37432 (Reel 33)
- Vouchers - Treasurer's Reports, #37431-42413 (Reel 34)
- Vouchers - Treasurer's Reports, #42412-47477 (Reel 35)
- Vouchers - Treasurer's Reports, #47476-53379 (Reel 36)
- Vouchers - Treasurer's Reports, #53378-50294 (Reel 37)
- Vouchers - Treasurer's Reports, #50293-56414 (Reel 38)
- Vouchers - Treasurer's Reports, #56413-53905 (Reel 39)
- Vouchers - Treasurer's Reports, #53904-60371 (Reel 40)
- Vouchers - Treasurer's Reports, #60370-58078 (Reel 41)
- Vouchers - Treasurer's Reports, #58077-64257 (Reel 42)
- Vouchers - Treasurer's Reports, #64256-70328 (Reel 43)
- Vouchers - Treasurer's Reports, #70327-66951 (Reel 44)
- Vouchers - Treasurer's Reports, #66950-73648 (Reel 45)
- Vouchers - Treasurer's Reports, #80209-77092 (Reel 46)
- Vouchers - Treasurer's Reports, #73647-80210 (Reel 47)
- Vouchers - Treasurer's Reports, #77091-82221 (Reel 48)
- Vouchers - Treasurer's Reports, #82220-87282 (Reel 49)
- Vouchers - Treasurer's Reports, #87281-91882 (Reel 50)
- Vouchers - Treasurer's Reports, #91881-1728 (Reel 51)
- Vouchers - Treasurer's Reports, #1709-8478 (Reel 52)
- Vouchers - Treasurer's Reports, #8477-4116 (Reel 53)
- Vouchers - Treasurer's Reports, #4115-16476 (Reel 54)
- Vouchers - Treasurer's Reports, #16475-13376 (Reel 55)
- Vouchers - Treasurer's Reports, #13375-28211 (Reel 56)
- Vouchers - Treasurer's Reports, #28210-24103 (Reel 57)
- Vouchers - Treasurer's Reports, #24102-34702 (Reel 58)
- Vouchers - Treasurer's Reports, #34701-39543 (Reel 59)
- Vouchers - Treasurer's Reports, #39542-35036 (Reel 60)
- Vouchers - Treasurer's Reports, #35035-44462 (Reel 61)
- Vouchers - Treasurer's Reports, #44461-57535 (Reel 62)
- Vouchers - Treasurer's Reports, #57534-52705 (Reel 63)
- Vouchers - Treasurer's Reports, #52704-67587 (Reel 64)
- Vouchers - Treasurer's Reports, #67586-60610 (Reel 65)
- Vouchers - Treasurer's Reports, #60609-71054 (Reel 66)
- Vouchers - Treasurer's Reports, #71053-80901 (Reel 67)
- Vouchers - Treasurer's Reports, #80900-90628 (Reel 68)
- Vouchers - Treasurer's Reports, #90627-101339 (Reel 69)
- Vouchers - Treasurer's Reports, #101338-113152 (Reel 70)
- Vouchers - Treasurer's Reports, #113151-124126 (Reel 71)
- Vouchers - Treasurer's Reports, #124125-115033 (Reel 72)
- Vouchers - Treasurer's Reports, #428481-126591 (Reel 73)
- Vouchers - Treasurer's Reports, #126590-129607, 1942-1943 (Reel 74)
- Vouchers - Treasurer's Reports, #129606-5221, 1943-1944 (Reel 75)
- Vouchers - Treasurer's Reports, #5220-8669, 1944-1945 (Reel 76)
- Vouchers - Treasurer's Reports, #8668-130714, 1945-1946 (Reel 77)
- Vouchers - Treasurer's Reports, #130713-16979, 1946-1947 (Reel 78)
- Vouchers - Treasurer's Reports, #16978-131933, 1947-1948 (Reel 79)
- Vouchers - Treasurer's Reports, #131932-133194, 1948-1949 (Reel 80)
- Vouchers - Treasurer's Reports, #133193-40914, 1949 (Reel 81)
- Vouchers - Treasurer's Reports, #40913-51974, 1949-1950 (Reel 82)
- Vouchers - Treasurer's Reports, #51973-113389, 1950-1951 (Reel 83)
- Vouchers - Treasurer's Reports, #133818-134946, 1951-1952 (Reel 84)
- Vouchers - Treasurer's Reports, #134945-30693, 1952 (Reel 85)
- Vouchers - Treasurer's Reports, #30692-136133, 1952-1953 (Reel 86)
- Vouchers - Treasurer's Reports, #136132-67753, 1953 (Reel 87)
- Vouchers - Treasurer's Reports, #67752-137208, 1953-1954 (Reel 88)
- Vouchers - Treasurer's Reports, #137207-79660, 1954-1955 (Reel 89)
- Vouchers - Treasurer's Reports, #79659-90679, 1955 (Reel 90)
- Vouchers - Treasurer's Reports, #90678-139124, 1956 (Reel 91)
- Vouchers - Treasurer's Reports, #139123-94418, 1956-1957 (Reel 92)
- Vouchers - Treasurer's Reports, #94417-140414, 1957 (Reel 93)
- Vouchers - Treasurer's Reports, #140413-142782, 1957-1958 (Reel 94)
- Vouchers - Treasurer's Reports, #142779-108048, 1958 (Reel 95)
- Vouchers - Treasurer's Reports, #108047-143431, 1958-1959 (Reel 96)
- Vouchers - Treasurer's Reports, #143430-142962, 1959 (Reel 97)
- Vouchers - Treasurer's Reports, #142961-109759, 1959 (Reel 98)
- Vouchers - Treasurer's Reports, #109758-145759, 1959-1960 (Reel 99)
- Vouchers - Treasurer's Reports, #145758-119997, 1960 (Reel 100)
- Vouchers - Treasurer's Reports, #119996-150245, 1960-1961 (Reel 101)
- Vouchers - Treasurer's Reports, #150244-158347, 1961-1962 (Reel 102)
- Vouchers - Treasurer's Reports, #158346-153724, 1962 (Reel 103)
- Vouchers - Treasurer's Reports, #153724-162421, 1962-1963 (Reel 104)
- Vouchers - Treasurer's Reports, #162420-168128, 1963 (Reel 105)
- Vouchers - Treasurer's Reports, #177338-168127, 1963 (Reel 106)
- Vouchers - Treasurer's Reports, #177337-183655, 1964 (Reel 107)
- Vouchers - Treasurer's Reports, #190697-183654, 1964 (Reel 108)
- Vouchers - Treasurer's Reports, #190696-198919, 1965-1966 (Reel 109)
- Vouchers - Treasurer's Reports, #198918-192275, 1965-1966 (Reel 110)
- Vouchers - Treasurer's Reports, #192274-132144, 1961-1962, 1966 (Reel 111)
- Cash Books - Books 1916-1921 (Reel 112)
- Cash Books - Books 1922-1923 (Reel 113)
- Cash Books - Books 1929-1940 (Reel 114)
- Cash Books - Books 1941-1957 (Reel 115)
- Cash Books - Books 1920-1933 (Reel 116)
- Cash Books - Books 1938-1960 (Reel 117)
- Financial Reports - Reports 1913-1920 (Reel 118)
- Financial Reports - Reports 1921-1930 (Reel 119)
- Financial Reports - Reports 1931-1938 (Reel 120)
- Financial Reports - Reports 1939-1947 (Reel 121)
- Financial Reports - Reports 1948-1955 (Reel 122)
- Financial Reports - Reports 1956-1962 (Reel 123)
- Financial Reports - Reports 1963-1971 (Reel 124)
- Financial Reports - Reports 1971-1979 (Reel 125)
- Payments, Appropriations, Misc. Grants - Univ. of Africa, Appropriations M.N.S. Agriculture (Reel 126)
- Payments, Appropriations, Misc. Grants - Univ. of Valle, Univ. of Ibadan and Univ. Philippines (Reel 127)
- Payments, Appropriations, Misc. Grants - Special Payments - Grants in Aid/Trial Balances (Reel 128)
- Payments, Appropriations, Misc. Grants - Foreign Appropriations, G.E.B. Payments/Grants/Domestic Appropriations (Reel 129)
- Payments, Appropriations, Misc. Grants - Payments, Appropriations, Misc. Grants A-C (Reel 130)
- Payments, Appropriations, Misc. Grants - Payments, Appropriations, Misc. Grants D-J (Reel 131)
- Payments, Appropriations, Misc. Grants - Payments, Appropriations, Misc. Grants K-Q (Reel 132)
- Payments, Appropriations, Misc. Grants - Payments, Appropriations, Misc. Grants R-T (Reel 133)
- Payments, Appropriations, Misc. Grants - Univ. of O.-Z, Co-op Progs, Misc. Section Administration (Reel 134)
- Payments, Appropriations, Misc. Grants - C.M.B. Paris Office - Miscellaneous Statements (Reel 135)
- Expenditures, Statements & Supp. Rec. - Geog. Records 1913-1935, Appropriations List 1929-1943, 1913-1935, 1929-1943 (Reel 136)
- Expenditures, Statements & Supp. Rec. - Expenditures 1913-1954, Geographical Statements A-C (Reel 137)
- Expenditures, Statements & Supp. Rec. - Geographical C-Z, 1913-1954 (Reel 138)
- Expenditures, Statements & Supp. Rec. - Appropriations List 1944-1955, 1952-1960 (Reel 139)
- Expenditures, Statements & Supp. Rec. - Expenditures 1913-1945 (Reel 140)
- Expenditures, Statements & Supp. Rec. - Expenditures 1931-1954 (Reel 141)
- Expenditures, Statements & Supp. Rec. - Expenditures 1935-1939 (Reel 142)
- Expenditures, Statements & Supp. Rec. - Budget Ledger 1941-1963, RF Expenditures 1940, 1941-1963, 1940 (Reel 143)
- Expenditures, Statements & Supp. Rec. - Geographical Records 1936-1954 (Reel 144)
- Expenditures, Statements & Supp. Rec. - Expenditures 1913-1963 (Reel 145)
- Expenditures, Statements & Supp. Rec. - Expenditures 1319-1915, Record of Securities, 1913-1915 (Reel 146)
- Expenditures, Statements & Supp. Rec. - RF Expenditures 1939 (Reel 147)
- Expenditures, Statements & Supp. Rec. - Geographical Records 1960-1963 (Reel 148)
- Expenditures, Statements & Supp. Rec. - Geographical Records 1955-1959 (Reel 149)
- Expenditures, Statements & Supp. Rec. - Endowment Buildings A-E and F-M (Reel 150)
- Expenditures, Statements & Supp. Rec. - Endowment Buildings N-S and T-Z (Reel 151)
- Expenditures, Statements & Supp. Rec. - Expenditures A-B and C-F (Reel 152)
- Expenditures, Statements & Supp. Rec. - Expenditures G-K and L-N (Reel 153)
- Expenditures, Statements & Supp. Rec. - Expenditures O-Z, T-Z (Reel 154)
- Expenditures, Statements & Supp. Rec. - Program Report 1913-1949, RF Statements (Reel 155)
- Miscellaneous - P.U.M.C. Budgets 1928-1933 (Reel 156)
- Miscellaneous - Special Fund Investments - R/MR 1939-1943, History of Funds 1913-1933, Treasurers Budgets 1947-1960, WRC Cash Books, Spelman Memorial Balance Sheets, Accounts Reports 1936-1961 (Reel 157)
- Miscellaneous - Senate Investigations Materials (Reel 158)
- Miscellaneous - Senate Investigations Materials (Reel 159)
- Miscellaneous - Audit Reports 1916-1935, B.S.H. Accounts Reports, Spelman Fund Brokers Statements 1936-1941, 1916-1935, 1936-1941 (Reel 160)
- Miscellaneous - LSRM Financial Statements 1919-1928, Spelman Fund Worksheets, Davison Fund, Sales/Worksheets (Reel 161)
- Miscellaneous - Worksheets 1931-1946 (Reel 162)
- Miscellaneous - Worksheets 1947-1958 (Reel 163)
- Miscellaneous - Tax Worksheets 1951-1976 (Reel 164)
- Miscellaneous - Tax Worksheets 1976, Rockefeller Institute Worksheets, G.D.B. Auditors Certificates 1904-1966, 1976, 1904-1966 (Reel 165)
- Miscellaneous - Auditors Certificates 1954-1966, Worksheets 1951-1965, Auditors Certificates 1913-1942, 1954-1966, 1951-1965, 1913-1942 (Reel 166)
- Miscellaneous - Auditors Certificates 1943-1973 (Reel 167)
- Payroll Registers - Payroll Register 1950-1956 (Reel 168)
- Payroll Registers - Payroll Register 1956-1960 (Reel 169)
- Payroll Registers - Payroll Accounts 1933-1938 (Reel 170)
- Payroll Registers - Payroll Accounts 1939-1943 (Reel 171)
- Journals - 1902-1928 (Reel 172)
- Journals - 1929-1942 (Reel 173)
- Journals - 1920-1932 (Reel 174)
- Ledgers - Expense Accounts 1931 (Reel 175)
- Ledgers - 1913-1926 (Reel 176)
- Ledgers - 1927-1943 (Reel 177)
- Securities Ledgers - Securities Ledgers 1913-1968 (Reel 178)
- Trial Balances - 1922-1968 (Reel 179)
- Finance Committee - 1913-1963 (Reel 180)